<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MTGANALYZE</title>
    <link>https://mtganalyze.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on MTGANALYZE</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>mtganalyze@gmail.com (Felix Weidemann)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>mtganalyze@gmail.com (Felix Weidemann)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mtganalyze.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Curve Considerations</title>
      <link>https://mtganalyze.github.io/post/curve_considerations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mtganalyze@gmail.com (Felix Weidemann)</author>
      <guid>https://mtganalyze.github.io/post/curve_considerations/</guid>
      <description>“What is the most important concept that Limited players should strive to understand?”.
Ben Stark: “Not being too fancy. Most games are won or lost by hitting your mana curve.”
In his Limited Information column Marshall Sutcliff once interviewed Ben Stark on limited advice. This particular piece was dubbed “THE TRUTH” and Ben Stark was spitting it. As one of his main messages Ben was pointing out the importance of having a mana curve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extracted Value</title>
      <link>https://mtganalyze.github.io/post/extract_value/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mtganalyze@gmail.com (Felix Weidemann)</author>
      <guid>https://mtganalyze.github.io/post/extract_value/</guid>
      <description>Let’s start with a small thought experiment: You are a semi-competitive and value-oriented Magic player. You just arrived at the site of the Grand Prix located near your home town. Due to your new job as an arctic explorer you rarely find time to play any bigger Magic events these days. It’s Friday and since you have no byes for the GP you are eager to play some trials. Surprisingly, Wizards Organized Play restructered the usual side event schedule.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skills and Scores</title>
      <link>https://mtganalyze.github.io/post/skills_and_scores/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mtganalyze@gmail.com (Felix Weidemann)</author>
      <guid>https://mtganalyze.github.io/post/skills_and_scores/</guid>
      <description>My brother once told me: “Playing day 2 of a GP is like playing on the Pro Tour – probably even harder”. Neither of us had yet played at the Pro Tour nor made a GP day 2 at that time, but in place of experience we at least had deep respect for the GP day 2 player field. However, regardless of my brother’s statement being right or wrong (it was wrong), the underlying idea is interesting: It must be only the finest players, who are capable of winning at least seven of nine rounds of exhausting tournament Magic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who am I?</title>
      <link>https://mtganalyze.github.io/post/who-am-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mtganalyze@gmail.com (Felix Weidemann)</author>
      <guid>https://mtganalyze.github.io/post/who-am-i/</guid>
      <description>It’s the sixth week of my paternity leave. I recently became a twin dad in addition to being just a dad. Being off work and spending hours changing diapers and holding a baby or two offers a lot of time to think about stuff. I am a passionate Magic player and I haven’t been touching cards in the last few weeks, thus I found myself to be thinking about Magic a lot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About this blog</title>
      <link>https://mtganalyze.github.io/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mtganalyze@gmail.com (Felix Weidemann)</author>
      <guid>https://mtganalyze.github.io/page/about/</guid>
      <description>Magic: the Gathering is a game bigger than its box. With over 10,000 individual cards Magic offers endless possibilities to play.
Using mathematical and statistical tools I try to find analytical solutions for imho interesting quantitative problems in and around the game. This blog won&amp;rsquo;t make you a better player but it will show you underappreciated puzzles within the world of Magic. You can find out more about me in my introductory post.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>